Chapter one.
Why don't you write a story?
Agatha, Mary, Clarissa Miller was board.
It was a winter morning in 1988.
And she was in bed because she was ill.
I'm feeling much better today,
she said to her mother, Clara.
I think I'll get up.
You're still ill, said Clara.
The doctor told you to stay in bed
and keep warm,
and that's what you're going to do.
Agatha was 18 years old at this time,
but in those days, daughters had
to do what their mothers told them.
But I'm bored.
Well, do something then, said her mother,
read a book or write a story?
Yes.
Why don't you write a story?
Right, a story said Agatha, surprised,
yes, her mother said like Match.
Madge was Agatha's sister,
she was 11 years older than Agatha
and sometimes wrote short stories
for magazines like Vanity Fair.
I don't think that I can write stories,
said Agatha.
How do you know, said her mother,
you've never tried.
And she went to find a pencil and paper.
Soon after, Agatha sat up in bed
and began to write a story.
It was called House of Beauty.
A strange story about dreams.
It wasn't a very good story.
She typed it on Maja's old typewriter
and sent it off to a magazine.
But they sent it back with a letter.
Thank you for sending us your story.
We are afraid we cannot publish it.
You must try again, said her mother.
Clara was always sure that her
daughters could do anything.
So Agatha went on writing stories
and sending them out to magazines.
But they all came back.
She was a little disappointed.
I'll try writing a novel.
She decided.
An idea came to her.
She remembered seeing a beautiful young
girl in a hotel in Cairo when she
was visiting Egypt with Klara.
The girl was always with two men,
one on each side of her.
One day, Agatha heard someone say,
that girl will have to decide
between them some time.
It was all that Agatha needed for an idea,
and she began writing.
It was not a detective novel.
It was the story of a young girl who lived
in Cairo and it was called
Snow upon the Desert.
It was really two long stories
put together to make a book.
When it was finished, Agatha sent
it to three or four publishers.
But they all sent it back.
Oh, dear, said Agatha.
What shall I do now?
Why don't you show it to Eden,
Phil Potts said Clara.
Eden Filberts was a writer
who lived near the Miller's.
During his life, he wrote more than 100
popular novels and many
plays for the theater.
Agatha was a little afraid of sending her
novel to this famous man,
but she agreed to do it and sent it off.
Mr.
Filberts was a good writer
and also a kind man.
He read Agatha's novel carefully
and wrote her a letter.
Some of your writing is very good,
so I am sending you a letter
to take to my agent Hughes Massie.
Agatha, still only 18 years old,
went to London on the train.
It was a long journey
more than 200 miles from her home
in Torquay, in Devon, and the trains
were not so fast in those days.
She was very shy and Hughes Massey
was a big, frightening man.
Agatha gave him the letter
from Eden Filberts.
Massie Redit talked with Agatha
for a while, then kept her book to read.
Agatha went home to wait.
Some months later, Marcy returned
snow upon the desert to her.
I do not think that I can find
a publisher for it, he wrote to her.
The best thing is to stop thinking about
it anymore and to write another book.
Agatha was disappointed.
She did write another book.
But some other important
things happened in her life.
First.